

Adriana Felisa Chávez De la Peña

Born in México, México City, March-7-1993 (26 y.o.) email adrifelcha@gmail.com Cellphone number 044 55 3205 1765

Resume

Experimental Psychologist formed at the National Autonomous University of México, interested in the study of Perception, Psychophysics, Cognitive Development and Psychometry. I've got experience in experimental design, data plotting, the conduction of statistical data analysis and Bayesian cognitive and statistical modeling, all these by means of R and Python programming.

COMPUTATIONAL SKILLS

Writing: LATEX, Office (Word, Excel Power Point, etc.)

OS : Mac, Windows

Data analysis and plotting: R (IDE: RStudio), Python (IDE: Spyder), SPSS y JASP

Experimental programming: Python (PsychoPy)
Website building: Python (PsychoPy)
HTML, CSS

I run the following sites:

http://www.bouzaslab25.com (My lab's website)

http://www.bouzaslab25.com/LabVirtual25/ (An interactive website for students to

interact with some mathematical models built within Psychology)

GENERAL SKILLS

Psychometry: Test development and data analysis

Communication skills: I've got experience being a teacher and making public presentations

Team work

Languages Spanish (Native) English (Fluent)

EDUCATION

Bachelor degree in Psychology at the National Autonomous University of Mexico (School of Psychology) G.A. 9.79/10.0.

Exchange Abroad Student at the University of California, Santa Barbara (Fall Quarter, 2014)

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

2014 - 2016 Student Council (Elected by the students of the School of Psychology to be their representative from May, 2014 to May, 2016)

2015- 2018 Lab member at Lab25, directed by Dr. Arturo Bouzas. Participation in the following research projects:

PAPIIT IN307214.

Proyecto: Learning under dynamic environments

PAPIME PE310016 (Head student)

Development of virtual tools for teaching cognitive and behavioral sciences.

PAPIIT IG 120818

Application of probabilistic models to the study of cognitive processes and algorithm design for service robots. Reference: abouzasr@gmail.com

WORKING EXPERIENCE

May 2018 – January 2019. Chief of Project (A-Level), at the National Institute for Educational Evaluation, at the General Department for the Evaluation of Teachers and Principals. Reference: Sandra Conzuelo Serrato sconzuelo@inee.edu.mx

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

2015–2017 English teacher at Instituto Mexicano Norteamericano de Cultura, for High schoolers.

2015–Present T.A. for Dr. Arturo Bouzas, in the following undergrad courses:

- Learning and Adaptative Behaviour I (2015-2018)
- Learning, Motivation and Cognition III (2015 y 2016)
- Research Workshop I, II y III (2015-2017)

•

June 2017 Summer courses given at the School of Psychology, UNAM:

- Statistical Thinking: an introduction
- Introduction to Bayesian modeling techniques
- A Python laboratory for behavioral sciences

January 2019 – Present. Teacher of Methodology at the private High School "Centro Educativo Jean Piaget"

Posters

- "Sensibility as a source of Bias in a signal detection task using optical illusions" at the V International Symposium of Behavioral Analysis (November, 2015; México City, México)
- "The Mirror Effect within Perception: Not another Recognition Memory study", at the Object Perception Attention and Memory Meeting (November, 2016; Boston, Massachussets)
- "Bayesian cognitive and statistical modeling applied to Signal Detection Theory and the Mirror Effect in a perceptual task." At the 52th Annual meeting of the Society for Mathematical Psychology (July, 2019; Montreal, Canada)

SYMPOSIA

- "Models of Adaptation in dynamic environments: Studies on detection, preferences and probability" at the VI International Symposium of Behavioral Analysis (November, 2017; Tlaxcala, Tlaxcala)
- "Cognitive diagnosis as a reflection tool for the teaching practice in elementary school in México" at the National Congress of Educational Research (November, 2019; *Guerrero, Acapulco*).

All probative documents are available upon request

This CV was updated on July 3rd, 2019